RESUME

Narottam Singh Bisht Fullstack Javascript Developer. 94170-06030, 98773-13056 narottambisht1995@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/narottam-bisht-37ab7686/

Objectives

To work for an organization which provides me the opportunity to improve my skills and knowledge and to grow along with the organizational objective. Currently learning Python.

Skill Set

- ✓ Strong problem solving ability.
- ✓ Excellent communication skills.
- ✓ Quick learner.
- ✓ Hard Worker and adaptable to every kind of situations.
- ✓ Open to Learn new technologies and frameworks.

Education

Qualificati	School/College	Uni./Board	Year	Marks/
on				Percentage
Class X	D. C. Model Sr. Sec.	P.S.E.B	March	1087/1300(83.61
	School		2011	%)
Class XII	D. C. Model Sr. Sec.	C.B.S.E	March	283/500(56.6 %)
	School		2013	
B.Tech.	Lala Lajpat Rai Instt.	Punjab	June 2017	4728/6350(74.45
(CSE)	Of Engg. And Tech.	Technical		%)
		University		/0)

Technical Skills

✓ **Technology:** NodeJs, Express.js, Sequelize, Mongoose, React, Redux, Redux

Saga.

✓ Database: MongoDB, MySql.✓ Tools: VS Code, Git, XCode.

Current Employment

Employer: Jellyfish Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Designation: NodeJs Developer.

Employment: April 2019 till Present.

Address: H-134, 2nd Floor, H Block, Sector 63, Noida.

Recent Projects

Project 1: Heffernan Insurance

Technology: React, Redux, Redux Saga.

Description: Heffernan is a CRM developed for the internal organization of

Heffernan Insurance brokers with backend in .Net and front end in React.

Website: <u>Heffernan Insurance</u>

Project 2: Patrapay

Technology: React, Hooks, Redux, Redux Saga

Description: Worked on front-end of an application for the payment module of patra corporation for their product QBIS. Which is a insurance portal for their clients.

Integrated stripe api's for Credit card payments and ACH payments.

Website: Patra pay

Project 3: Timesheets

Technology: NodeJs, Express, Sequelize, MySql and deployed on AWS EC2.

Description: Web application that have admin panel and user panel and allows our own company employees to log the time and tasks of their everyday projects. Its a time tracker or task tracker application for any organization.

Website: <u>Timesheets - JFT</u>

Previous Employment

Employer: Redian Software LLC, Noida (Javascript Developer)

Employment: September 2018 till April 2019

Employer: Devi Techno Solutions, Ferozepur, Punjab (NodeJs Developer)

Employment: October 2017 till April 2018

Personal Details

D.O.B: 12th June, 1995.

Gender: Male.

Languages: English, Hindi, Punjabi.

Hobbies: Surfing On Internet, Reading Novels and Autobiographies.

Permanent Address: #20, Street No. 25, Basti Tankan Wali, Ferozepur City,

Ferozepur, Punjab

Current Address: Kings Camp PG, M-45, Street No. 7, Sector 66, Noida.

Summary

Energetic, results-oriented software engineer with 2+ years of experience in software development industry. A diligent and avid team player who never backs down. A person with a passion for coding and learning new technologies and frameworks. In the past 2 years I had exposure to variety of javascript frameworks like NodeJs, ReactJs, Redux, Redux Saga, Sequelize, Mongoose, PassportJs and GIT with which I have worked on many web applications both front-end and back-end. Currently I am learning Python as well because it intrigues me how much this language can do. I have excellent comm. Skills. I have been awarded best student of the year award in my college as well.